

ZUBAIR BIN KHALID

BIM ENGINEER (MECHANICAL)

EMAIL: zubairbinkhalid1275@gmail.com PHONE: +91-9891166940

4+ Years of rich industry experience on designing & planning of a wide range of built environment with keen interest in smart BIM Technologies for sustainable construction. Exposure in working in projects of various verticals covering Metro, Commercial & Residential buildings in multicultural environment. Always willing to explore new software and ideas.

April 2017 - Present BIM ENGINEER, INTEC INFRA TECHNOLOGIES currently working for the prestigious NOMAN M. COLE, JR. POLLUTION CONTROL PLANT (USA) project on Revit 2020,

JUNE 2016 – APRIL 2017 INTERN, SK DESIGN CONSULTANTS worked as an intern for a period of 8 Months as an HVAC Design Engineer.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Technology (Mechanical Engineering) from Greater Noida College Of Technology (Abdul Kalam Technical University) 2012-2016
- 10th & 12th Standard From Dev Samaj Modern School (CBSE Board), Delhi 2009-2012

EXPERIENCE:

(AUGUST - OCTOBER , RELIANCE DASSAULT NAGPUR LOD 350)

- HVAC Modelling for Nagpur airport
- Coordination with MEP, Architecture and Structure.
- Generated Detailed design Sheets.

(FEBRUARY - MARCH 2020, OUTSOURCE EMPLOYEE FOR COLAS RAIL, KUALA LUMPUR, MALAYSIA Duration:1 month) PROJECT – EQPS AND 16 SIERRA STATION

- Electrical detailed modeling (LOD 400) for TPSS, Coordination with MEP services for generating IFC sheets
- Creating Revit families for Mounting standards and generating mounting standard sheets.

(DECEMBER 2019 – JANUARY 2020 - BIOLSKY, US)

- HVAC detailed modeling (LOD 400) for Residential Buildings, for generating IFC sheets.
- Generated the Documentation sheets of MEP services and Created families for the annotations with coordination with technical consultants overseas. Initial set up of the presentation of sheet standards as per the client requirement.

(NOVEMBER 2019 - OUTSOURCE EMPLOYEE FOR COLAS RAIL, KUALA LUMPUR, MALAYSIA Duration:1 month) PROJECT – JINS AND 16 SIERRA STATION

- Electrical detailed modeling (LOD 400) for TPSS, Coordination with MEP services for generating IFC sheets
- Creating Revit families for Mounting standards and generating mounting standard sheets.

MARCH 2019- OCTOBER 2019, RESIDENTIAL APARTMENTS ISABELLAVELD, VUGHT, NETHERLANDS

- HVAC and Plumbing Modelling as per the Dutch Revit Standards (NLRS)
- MEP Coordination and generating IFC sheets for site execution.

JANUARY 2019- MARCH 2019 Rose and Crown Hotel, Alderney, UK

Concept HVAC Design for the Hotel, All Calculations were done on Spreadsheets.

- Heat Load Calculations
- Ventilation Calculations
- Static Pressure Calculations
- Pump Head Calculations
- Equipment Selection
- Single Line Diagram in AutoCAD showing the major routings.
- Design Basis Report (DBR)
- HVAC Load List for electrical and Deliverable List.

JUNE 2018 – DECEMBER 2018, STATION LEAD, KLES STATION, KVMRT LINE 2 KUALA LUMPUR MALAYSIA (LOD 400)

MEP Modeling & Coordination task for generating the ISD, CSD & SEM drawings for KLES Station. Model Coordination was carried out through Navisworks 2018 in a federated environment, generated the clash report and resolved the clashes in Revit.

• Generated the Documentation sheets of TPSS services and Created families for the annotations with coordination with technical consultants overseas. Initial set up of the presentation of sheet standards as per the client requirement.

(OUTSOURCE EMPLOYEE FOR FOCUS DESIGN PARTNERS, QATAR), (Duration: 3 Months) PROJECT - AL BAYT STADIUM

MEP Modeling & Coordination task for generating the Shop Drawings for Site Execution. Coordinated with the Onsite Client and converting LOD 300 Model to LOD 400. Created Mark Ups for Sub contractors and Coordinated with the Site Engineers.

(OUTSOURCE EMPLOYEE FOR WSP NOIDA, INDIA), (Duration: 5 Months)

PROJECT-YAS SOUTH (Retail And Hospitality, Mixed used High rise Building, Abu Dhabi)

- MEP Modeling & Coordination task for generating the documents for the tender stage.
 Coordinated with the client at overseas location and providing the necessary documents and details
- Generated the Documentation sheets of MEP services and Created families for the annotations Initial set up of the presentation of sheet standards as per the client requirement.

APRIL 2017 – JULY 2017 KVMRT LINE 2 KUALA LUMPUR MALAYSIA

MEP Modeling & Coordination task for generating the ISD, CSD & SEM drawings for various stations in KVMRT LINE 2 like HKLX, KLES, BMSS, BMNS, TTWS and APPS.

DUBLIN AIRPORT (Baggage Handling), MEP Services Modelling on POINT CLOUD Revit. Retracing the MEP services already build using Point Cloud. Modelling was done with the support of softwares like TRUEVIEW and AUTODESK RECAP.

KEY SKILLS

- Proficient knowledge of MEP services: HVAC, Water supply, Drainage & Firefighting.
- 3D Modeling on Revit, documentation, coordination, scheduling and quality checking.
- Reviewing consultant design drawings and specification. Ensuring construction documents accuracy based on discipline model.
- Highlight the discrepancies in the contract drawing/specification and raise RFIs accordingly.
- Create 3D model of MEP services based on contract drawing, specification and technical submittals. Collaborate and Coordinate with other disciplines design changes and model challenges in Autodesk Navisworks Platform.

SOFTWARES WORKED ON

- Revit 2013-2020
- Navisworks 2015-2018
- Revit Fabrication 2018-2019
- AutoCAD 2013-2018.
- MS Office Suite
- Bluebeam Revu
- Trueview & Autodesk Recap

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Nationality Indian
- Present Organization Intec Infra Technologies Pvt. Ltd
- Date of Birth 16th February 1994
- Language Proficiency English, Hindi, Urdu.
- Marital Status Single
- Contact Number +91-9891166940.